

I am Adam Kosecki, a highly-analytical application developer with 15+ years of professional experience. MVP criteria focused, my teams build things that are lean and clean; from straightforward, comprehensible design elements to robust, pivotable code.

I strive to understand the problem we are solving from all angles before outlining a solution. My solutions are a fair compromise between speed and quality; form and function; seriousness and fun.

I am a leader. I make decisions when appropriate, and defer or delegate without shame. People respect me and enjoy working with me.

847-528-2326 adamkosecki@gmail.com

full resume: adamkosecki.com

TECH & TOOLS

JS, Next.JS, React, Node, Tailwind, MaterialUI, OpenAI, Supabase, SQL, Ember.JS, PHP, Laravel, More

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, Programming Emphasis Minor in Psychology

Western Illinois University 2000-2004

HISTORY

Latchel

PRINCIPAL DEVELOPER
2019 - PRESENT

Latchel is a property maintenance automation platform that handles the entire lifecycle of a maintenance request, including intake, diagnostics, contractor sourcing, scheduling, payment processing, and communications. It frees property managers from the labor-intensive task of coordinating repairs between tenants, contractors, and property owners.

As the company's first technical hire, I was in a position to provide daily impact for the organization. I formed a strong relationship with the product team, led the engineers, and architected our biggest solutions, including:

- An Al powered maintenance request intake process that simplified request submission from a 10 step diagnostic process to a single form input, reducing submission time from minutes to seconds. The solution increased problem identification accuracy and eliminated junk requests.
- Automated, prioritized contractor queue to dispatch work offers. The solution eliminated redundant, error-prone human operations while providing more predictable SLAs.
- Pivoted the product focus to offer an integrated experience, allowing our software partners to
 embed our contractor sourcing application into their own property management software,
 within minutes. The solution provided a seamless experience for their customers; allowing
 them to create and manage maintenance coordination without leaving their app.

SpotMii

CO-FOUNDER/DEVELOPER 2017-2019

SpotMii was created to provide fitness consumers a way to discover new and exciting fitness facilities, and streamline the payment and check-in process for individuals that frequent multiple gyms. Users could purchase single-use passes for drop-in access and scheduled classes. Payments and scheduling were handled in-app.

As a co-founder of SpotMii, I successfully designed, built, and deployed demonstrative beta versions of our apps that enabled us to secure an angel round of funding. We completed and launched the product in early 2019.

- · Geo-located, two-sided marketplace consisting of discrete consumer and affiliate apps.
- · SPA/JS app deployed to iOS App Store and Android/Google Play via Cordova.
- · Consumer facing app, affiliate app for gym owners, and an intranet for internal moderation.
- · Ember.js SPA design & implementation
- · PHP/Phalcon API design & implementation
- MySQL DBA
- AWS infrastructure



HISTORY (continued)

MogulMind

CO-FOUNDER/DEVELOPER 2016-2018

I designed and built MogulMind: an Ember.js SPA that provided insight into real estate investments, helping to calculate ROI for flips and rentals, enabling users to make better investment decisions. MogulMind was a first-to-market web app providing traditional real estate investment calculations for the modern world, and proprietary investment advice through AI.

- As the founder's first partner, I took MogulMind from napkin idea to launch and customer acquisition. I was the root of anything technical or design related.
- · SPA: Ember.js design & implementation
- · REST API: PHP/Phalcon/MySQL design & implementation
- · Marketing website design & implementation
- · AWS infrastructure

Clear Software

VP OF PRODUCT / LEAD DEVELOPER
2015-2016

Transitioned Clear Software, a no-code SAP integration solution, from an on-premise, single-user solution to a multi-tenant, SaaS, cloud application. Evangelized best practices and modern development techniques. Clear went on to be acquired by Microsoft.

HelpSystems

SENIOR DEVELOPER 2014-2016 Developed and deployed an HTML5, mobile-first invoicing application in PHP/AngularJS/MySql to facilitate an end-to-end process for online ordering and payments. The application included a robust API allowing it to integrate with multiple, disparate back-end legacy systems.

Implemented ETL processes to migrate and synchronize data between HelpSystems and Network Automation servers throughout the acquisition process

Network Automation

LEAD DEVELOPER, LEAD UI DESIGN 2005-2015

Created entire public web entity for company (no longer online as of 2019), including all visual design elements, technological decisions (language/framework/server), coding, SEO decisions, optimization for user experience & retention, and... everything else:

- Built a homegrown shopping cart system: processed every purchase/transaction made through the company. Responsible not only for collecting payment, but issuing products and licenses to customers.
- Built a homegrown Customer Resource Center: video tutorials, knowledge-base articles, product version history, etc. Included an internal CMS.
- Built a homegrown, drag-n-drop HTML email creation tool for our newsletters
 (Mailchimp before Mailchimp). Integrated with our blog, etc. to easily drag-n-drop existing articles to create an HTML newsletter. Included mass-mailing system and subscription management.
- Built a homegrown support ticketing system.
- Built a homegrown Channel/Partner Portal: an application to provide sales collateral, news, lead registration, etc for resellers/VARs/strategic partners.
- Built our homegrown customer account application (address info, license keys, product maintenance subscriptions, etc).
- · Marketing and pre-sale content: press releases, news, case studies, blog.
- Served as company DBA, implementing best practices including full normalization of existing MS SQL database. Wrote and revised countless queries, views, and stored procedures for various organizational departments.
- · Inherited, managed, enhanced, and enriched existing (homegrown) corporate CRM.